Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to make our eye a bit more smart.
If I go similarly, my ad will continue walking.
Although as soon as it hits a wall, it acts kind of dumb.
It'll just stand there.
We're going to make it so that whenever I hit a wall, it will stand there and then turn around and
move in the opposite direction.
So let's set this up.
We go back to our account and beep and go over to where we set up the handle movement custom event.
Just move these nodes into some free space.
So after we make our character move, we just want to drag up here and look for mine, trace for objects.
So we're going to be doing a line trace to see if there's anything in front of our Scampton character
where we want this line trace to start.
We just want to right click up or get actor location.
And hook us up to start and where we want this to end.
We want this to end a couple of units in front of our Stanton character, whichever direction they're
facing.
So to do that, we're going to right click and we'll get actor forward vector, then off the return
body.
Just drag off it for multiply.
Then here, just right click and it will spit out the pin.
And here we're only concerned with the value in the X because our sanctum is only moving along the x
axis.
Just put a value around 100.
I had a struggle at.
And connect this into here.
So we're going to be starting our line trace wherever our skin is located, and we'll be in get 100
units in front of wherever our Scantron is located.
The objects we're going to be looking for, if we just drag up here for make array and just go add pin,
add pin.
The first one, we want it to be, well, static.
These are the types of collision that our cubes have right now.
The second one we're going to have is, well, dynamic.
Sometimes static matters inside of an engine like these cubes have a well dynamic collision.
So we want to just have that type specified there just in case.
And the third one, we want it to be PWM.
If I go to the viewport and just like this capsule collision or our character blueprints have port collisions.
So let's scroll down.
We can see the custom preset is PWM.
The reason we're adding PWM is in case our enemy bumps into another enemy, it will just turn around
and move.
All have access to ignore.
We just want to drag up here and look for mic array and just right click and forget their character.
I don't want my eye to turn around if it ever bumped into my player character, so we're just adding
that there.
Then if this line tries ever hit something, this return value is going to be true.
And if this is true, then we're going to make off and stand still and then turn around.
So over to just drag and look for to once.
After this do want we want to drag in our character movement and just set our enemies walking speed
to be there.
So we'll set Max walk speed and just leave this earth value of zero.
Then we're going to have a delay.
This is going to be how long it's going to take our enemy to turn around and start walking again, to
make this flexible, just right click and promote this to travel and make this instant editable and
just call this wait time.
I'm going to compile this.
And for now, I'm going to give it a default.
Wait time of three.
After this wait time, we're going to make our enemy move again.
So I'm just going to copy these notes.
And pace them here and we're going to make our enemy walk again.
Unless Max walks, we'd just right click and promote this terrible.
And compile and just give this a max boot speed of 100.
If I just go to my character movement and look from the details for warp speed.
Only my enemy has a max speed of 600.
So that's the speed is going to be that this is quite fast.
So to be flexible on a bumping and play.
I'm going to set my characters.
Max Warp speed.
To be whatever is inside of this variable.
That way you can just change it to a different value if you want to.
Then after we do this, we're going to make our eye move in the opposite direction.
In order to do this, we want to drag in our movement direction and just drag up here and let go multiply.
We're going to multiply this by negative one.
So if I just select by movement direction by default, this has a value of one.
If I multiply this by negative one, then this will become negative one and my inner will move in the
opposite direction.
If this value was ever negative one and I multiply it by a negative one, then this value will become
one.
So I'm just going to drag in my direction and offset and hook this up here.
Then after I've done this, I'm going to put this into the do want to reset.
And then I'm just going to double click and move this down.
So I'm just going to briefly explain what we've just done.
So I've added a D once here because I don't want this constantly spammed whenever my eye hits one of
these, well, static bar dynamic or -- objects.
Then I'm going to tell my area to stop moving.
We're going to wait a couple of seconds, then we'll give my eye speed back.
Then we'll make it move in the opposite direction just so that we can visually see our line trace under
draw debug type.
Just change this to be for duration and go compile and save.
So now we can see if everything is working.
So now if you see that little red line when it hits, that wall should go green.
So it's gone.
GREENE So it's very hard to see.
Then my eye turned around and is now moving.
So I'll go to this wall, but wait 3 seconds and then turn around.
So now I is a bit more clever.